Pacific Life Community records M2219
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Pacific Life Community records
1972-1980
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Pacific Life Community
Aldridge, Robert C.
Coleman, Peggy J.
Purcell, Lawrence P.
M2219
3.0 Linear Feet (4 boxes and 1 map folder)
Biographical / Historical
Pacific Life Community began as a small group committed to resisting the coming of Trident [nuclear submarines] to the Pacific Northwest. It was founded in 1975 by Robert (Bob) and Janet Aldridge and Jim and Shelley Douglass (along with about a dozen others).
Content Description
Materials consist of publications, notes, correspondence, newspaper clippings, minute meetings, photographs and related ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert C. Aldridge, Peggy J. Coleman, and Lawrence P. Purcell; 2017. Accession MSS 2017-127.
Peace movements -- United States; Antinuclear movement -- United States; Trident (Weapons systems); Pacific Life Community
- 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- January - April 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- May - June 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- July - August 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- September - October 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- November - December 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- January - February 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- April - May 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- June - July 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- August - September 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- October 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- November - December 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- January - May 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- June - August 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- September - December 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- January - May 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1978 - correspondence (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Other groups - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Other groups - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Other groups: PLC local (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Other groups - Trident United Staes (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Other groups - international (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Other groups - Western United States (Box 3, Folder 6)
- January - May 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- June - December 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 1979 - correspondence (Box 3, Folder 8)
- PLC Northwest - live without Trident (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Live without Trident (Map-folder 5)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: PLC, local (Box 3, Folder 10)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: Trident, United States (Box 3, Folder 11)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: international (Half-box 4, Folder 1)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: other groups in California (Half-box 4, Folder 2)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: other Western United States (Half-box 4, Folder 3)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: national movement (Half-box 4, Folder 4)
- PLC 1980 yearbook: resources (Half-box 4, Folder 5)
- Binder covers - copies (Half-box 4, Folder 6)
- 1973 - 1980 oversize (Map-folder 4)